{
  "heading": "Start the Practise Sheet",
  "topics": [
    {
      "heading": "The Hound of the Baskervilles - Part 1 Questions",
      "questions": [
        {
          "questionNo": 1,
          "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'surmise'?",
          "options": [
            "suppose that something is true without having evidence to confirm it",
            "Guess",
            "Conjecture",
            "All of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "Guess and Conjecture are synonyms of Surmise."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 2,
          "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'moor'?",
          "options": [
            "a tract of open uncultivated upland, typically covered with heather",
            "Bushy, cultivated land",
            "Completely Barren land",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The answer is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 3,
          "question": "The wagonette was paid off and ordered to return to:",
          "options": [
            "Frankland’s house",
            "The Hall",
            "Merripit house",
            "Coombe Tracey"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "The wagonette was paid off and ordered to return to Coombe Tracey forthwith, while we started to walk to Merripit House."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 4,
          "question": "What is the Point of view of the story?",
          "options": [
            "Omniscient",
            "First Person",
            "Innocent Eye",
            "Second person"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "The story is told by his assistant Dr. Watson. Thus, it is a character who is a close associate of the protagonist; the speaker employs the pronouns 'I,' 'me,' 'we', and 'us.' The entire story will be told through his eyes, and readers are limited to understanding only what he or she is aware of."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 5,
          "question": "Most of the action in the first part of the story happens during:",
          "options": [
            "Late night",
            "Early evening",
            "Night",
            "Afternoon"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The following references are sequentially presented: I had often suffered under it, but never more so than during that long drive in the darkness. It is already ten o’clock. Our success and even his life may depend upon his coming out before the fog is over the path. The night was clear and fine above us. The stars shone cold and bright, while a half-moon bathed the whole scene in a soft, uncertain light. Before us lay the dark bulk of the house, its serrated roof and bristling chimneys hard outlined against the silver-spangled sky."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 6,
          "question": "What is the author’s purpose behind telling us about Sherlock Holmes’s peculiar habit concerning his plans associated with investigation?",
          "options": [
            "It is an important insight about the detective’s character sketch.",
            "It builds into a two-fold suspense, one for the reader and the other for the Dr. Watson and Holmes’s other associates.",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The answer is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 7,
          "question": "Merripit house is owned by:",
          "options": [
            "Jack Stapleton",
            "Frankland",
            "Lestrade",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "That is Merripit House and the end of our journey. I must request you to walk on tiptoe and not to talk above a whisper. The Baskerville estate is owned by Sir Henry. Frankland already has a house which Holmes and his associates have already crossed while coming to the Merripit House. Lestrade is the inspector from Scotland Yard who came to assist Sherlock Holmes in the case involving the Baskervilles."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 8,
          "question": "What is the author’s purpose behind focussing on the fog?",
          "options": [
            "The fog is of utmost importance because it helps the author to inject and heighten the element of tension, mystery and suspense into and of the atmospheric setting",
            "If the fog covers the path on which Sir Henry Baskerville is walking, Holmes and his associates would not be able to see the hound and hence would not be able to save Sir Henry from its vicious paws.",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 9,
          "question": "What was found on the round table in the dining room of Merripit’s House?",
          "options": [
            "Cigar",
            "Coffee",
            "Cigar",
            "Both A and B"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "There were only two men in the room, Sir Henry and Stapleton. They sat with their profiles towards me on either side of the round table. Both of them were smoking cigars, and coffee and wine were in front of them."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 10,
          "question": "“If he isn’t out in a quarter of an hour the path will be covered. In half an hour we won’t be able to see our hands in front of us.” Who said the above words:",
          "options": [
            "Lestrade",
            "Stapleton",
            "Holmes",
            "Dr. Watson, the narrator"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "Holmes struck his hand passionately upon the rock in front of us and stamped his feet in his impatience. “If he isn’t out in a quarter of an hour the path will be covered. In half an hour we won’t be able to see our hands in front of us.”"
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 11,
          "question": "What was Jack Stapleton by profession?",
          "options": [
            "A doctor",
            "A caretaker",
            "A servant",
            "A naturalist"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "As I watched them Stapleton rose and left the room, while Sir Henry filled his glass again and leaned back in his chair, puffing at his cigar. I heard the creak of a door and the crisp sound of boots upon gravel. Looking over, I saw the naturalist pause at the door of an out-house in the corner of the orchard."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 12,
          "question": "“Yes, we shall make our little ambush here. Get into this hollow, Lestrade. You have been inside the house, have you not, Watson? Can you tell the position of the rooms? What are those latticed windows at this end?” The above words indicate that:",
          "options": [
            "Holmes had earlier sent Watson to the moors to check the Merripit House",
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 13,
          "question": "Why were Holmes and associates surprised to see only Jack Stapleton and Sir Henry in the Merripit House?",
          "options": [
            "They were expecting another friend",
            "They were expecting a lady in the house",
            "Both A and B",
            "They were expecting Frankland"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "I saw him rejoin his guest, and I crept quietly back to where my companions were waiting to tell them what I had seen. “You say, Watson, that the lady is not there?” Holmes asked when I had finished my report. “No.” “Where can she be, then, since there is no light in any other room except the kitchen?” “I cannot think where she is.”"
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 14,
          "question": "What is the meaning of the word “Inexorably”?",
          "options": [
            "in a way that is impossible to stop or prevent.",
            "Probably",
            "Feasible to uncontrol",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 15,
          "question": "I have said that over the great …………………there hung a dense, white fog. It was drifting slowly in our direction and banked itself up like a wall on that side of us, low but thick and well defined.",
          "options": [
            "Moor",
            "Dartmoor",
            "The Hall",
            "Grimpen Mire"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory since the extract is from the text of the story itself."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 16,
          "question": "As per the Freytag’s Pyramid, what stages of the plot did we cover in the first part of the story The Hound of the Baskervilles?",
          "options": [
            "Conflict",
            "Exposition",
            "Rising action",
            "Both B and C"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "Conflict is the essence of any story. It runs throughout the story up until the denouement."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 17,
          "question": "The mood of a literary passage is made evident by the setting and language the author uses for a certain story.",
          "options": [
            "Correct",
            "Incorrect"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 18,
          "question": "Stunted means:",
          "options": [
            "Beaten to death",
            "Having been prevented from growing or developing properly",
            "Starved to death",
            "Sacrificed something special for someone else’s benefit"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 19,
          "question": "During their conversation, Jack Stapleton had left Sir Henry in the dining room of the Merripit House for some time and joined him again. Where did Stapleton go and where is that place located?",
          "options": [
            "An out-house outside the stunted orchard",
            "A store room in the corner of the orchard",
            "A store room outside the stunted orchard",
            "An out-house in the corner of the orchard"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "As I watched them Stapleton rose and left the room, while Sir Henry filled his glass again and leaned back in his chair, puffing at his cigar. I heard the creak of a door and the crisp sound of boots upon gravel. Looking over, I saw the naturalist pause at the door of an out-house in the corner of the orchard."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 20,
          "question": "What is described as 'a strange ship upon a shadowy sea' by the narrator, Dr. Watson?",
          "options": [
            "The Baskerville Hall",
            "The Merripit House",
            "The outhouse of the Merripit house",
            "Frankland’s house"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "Dr. Watson states 'As we watched it the fog-wreaths came crawling round both corners of the house and rolled slowly into one dense bank on which the upper floor and the roof floated like a strange ship upon a shadowy sea.'"
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 21,
          "question": "A sound of quick steps broke the silence of the moor. Crouching among the stones we stared intently at the silver-tipped bank in front of us. The steps grew louder, and through the fog, as through a curtain, there stepped the man whom we were awaiting. Who were Holmes and his team waiting for?",
          "options": [
            "Jack Stapleton",
            "Dr. Mortimer",
            "Sir Henry Baskerville",
            "The old man servant of Merripit House"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "There were only two men in the room, Sir Henry and Stapleton. They sat with their profiles towards me on either side of the round table. Both of them were smoking cigars, and coffee and wine were in front of them. Stapleton was talking with animation, but the baronet looked pale and distraught. Perhaps the thought of that lonely walk across the ill-omened moor was weighing heavily upon his mind……He looked round at him in surprise as he emerged into the clear, starlit night. Then he came swiftly along the path, passed close to where we lay, and went on up the long slope behind us. As he walked he glanced continually over either shoulder, like a man who is ill at ease…."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 22,
          "question": "In order to judge the tone of a passage it is important to identify the central feeling of the narrator by reading the entire passage carefully and understand his/her concern from his/her perspective.",
          "options": [
            "Correct",
            "Incorrect"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 23,
          "question": "A surprise attack by people lying in wait in a concealed position. is the meaning of:",
          "options": [
            "Crouch",
            "Forbade",
            "Ambush",
            "Ordeal"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        }
      
      ]
    }
  ]
}
